<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Examined Algorithms</title>
    <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Examined Algorithms</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2020 Nathaniel Forde</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 10:19:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nathanielf.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Estimation and Histogram Approximation</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/bayesian_ab_tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/bayesian_ab_tests/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re pretty confident of your recent bet. All the other gamblers at the table have taken the other side of the bet. Just for fun, assume all other gamblers in the casino have bet against you. The game is in the first quarter and things are looking good, but how do you evaluate now whether you should hedge your bets before final quarter is called? This kind of scenario is typical in an imbalanced A/B test where we haven&amp;rsquo;t randomised the samples, and we&amp;rsquo;re letting it ride based entirely on vibes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pooling Information in PYMC</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/pooling_experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/pooling_experiments/</guid>
      <description>Two heads are better than one and fools rarely differ. It&amp;rsquo;s an old trope. A tension to be navigated everytime we combine information across different sources. Can we trust the aggregate opinion? If we poll the masses do the summary statistics measure a common source of variation or represent an crass abstraction over individual particulars? But if we do trust the sources, how far can we generalise from the historic record?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Processes and Inferred Networks</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/spatial_correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/spatial_correlation/</guid>
      <description>Of the varied ways in which you add to the world, you might imagine a modest influence over your social network. Of all those connections their cumulative impact is likely less than you imagine. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re a new parent hopeful to leave a positive impression on your children, but conscious of friends ignored. Attention is a resource, so the periphery of our network may suffer neglect or fall out altogether - some individuals are sacrificed, others deliberately culled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Decisions &amp; Model Comparison </title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/bayes_decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/bayes_decision/</guid>
      <description>Most days we face an infinite horizon of future decisions without being overwhelmed. A sequence of such decisions can compound, or reduce that certainty. But we tend to focus on the exaggerated drama of the momentous choice. Even when change is gradual and cumulative, history tells of a tale of pivot points, epic junctures and transformative events. Two paths diverge in a woods and we choose one. An array of possibilities suddenly open before us, or gets collapsed into a cul de sac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wheat from Chaff: Maximum Entropy and Information</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/wheat_from_chaff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/wheat_from_chaff/</guid>
      <description>There is a rumour of ignorant fish; so involved in the ocean they fail to notice the water around them, what it is and what it could be. There is another cliche about the internet and its denizens drowning in information. There is something to both these images, but the second is too charitable. It suggests a light consistency to the viscous texture of the flow, instead of the congealed sludge that drips down our throat choking off the air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trains, Planes ...Utility and Maximum Likelihood</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/mle_utility_and_choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/mle_utility_and_choice/</guid>
      <description>In The Century of Self Adam Curtis&amp;rsquo; spiralling survey of the 20th century we&amp;rsquo;re shown how the Freud&amp;rsquo;s ideas seeped into public consciousness. How they were taken and deployed by ad-men and marketing gurus to sell our own initimated desires back to ourselves. There is a conceit of individuality and uniqueness - that our mind is our own and the choices we make are ours alone to know and learn from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing, Simultaneity and IV Regression</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/pricing_a_potted_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/pricing_a_potted_history/</guid>
      <description>Demand curve analysis is the academic study of tolerable robbery and stock market manias spike demand curves. You&amp;rsquo;ve likely seen the cobweb like diagrams that chart the trajectories of supply and demand as a function of price. These are aids to estimate the depth of your pockets. Acceptable elascticities of pricing always emerge as a consequence of tolerable changes in demand. A pricing strategy is a question of latitude, how far can we stretch your budget to account for &amp;ldquo;surplus value&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haavelmo&#39;s Autonomous laws in Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/forecasting_grue_timeseries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/forecasting_grue_timeseries/</guid>
      <description>In 1944 Trygve Haavelmo could argue sincerely that the hostility to mathematical statistics in economics was a mistake. He could argue that, in fact, economic questions could be phrased in the language of probability. Today that observation is palpably anachronistic, owing to the current trend of equating economists with soothsayers while expecting similar arcana and spell craft. The reality falls short of magic and is more interesting than the fantasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factor Analysis and Construct Validity in Psychology</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/theoretical_risks_meehl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/theoretical_risks_meehl/</guid>
      <description>In a prescient paper in the 1970s Paul Meehl wrote about the lack of cumulative success in the psychologocial sciences, and how this should be attributed to poor methodology rather than the sheer difficulty of the subject. He elaborates an impressive list of problems for modeling any psychological process. Common themes criss-cross the list and interact with one another in ways which could make you despair for the discipline. So it is, I think, somewhat surprising that Meehl locates the main problem not in the subject, but in the method of significance testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/extras/notable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/extras/notable/</guid>
      <description> Meehl and Factor Analysis Haavelmo&amp;rsquo;s Hierarchical Laws Scarab: Hugo Website Theme  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/extras/notable_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/extras/notable_2/</guid>
      <description> Book Project: Examining Algorithms  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psi, Replication and Bayesian Evidence</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/replication_and_cross_validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/replication_and_cross_validation/</guid>
      <description>Daryl Bem did not literally explode peoples brains, but his proofs of the possibility shook psychology to the core. In a short and precise paper Feeling the Future Bem set out to show that there was good evidence for the existence of human pre-cognition. Paradoxical as it sounds he succeeded. His research coincided with the burgeoning realisation that there was a replication crisis in psychology, yet he presented his work as invitation to further replication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>