<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Examined Algorithms</title>
    <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Examined Algorithms</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2020 Nathaniel Forde</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:19:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nathanielf.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Processes and Inferred Networks</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/spatial_correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/spatial_correlation/</guid>
      <description>Of the varied ways in which you add to the world, you might imagine a modest influence over your social network. Of all those connections their cumulative impact is likely less than imagined even when crudely measured. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re a new parent hopeful to leave a positive impression on your children, but conscious of friends ignored. The central nodes our social networks change, the periphery may suffer neglect or fall out of the network altogether - some individuals are sacrificed, others deliberately culled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trains, Planes ...Utility and Maximum Likelihood</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/mle_utility_and_choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/mle_utility_and_choice/</guid>
      <description>In The Century of Self Adam Curtis&amp;rsquo; spiralling survey of the 20th century we&amp;rsquo;re shown how the Freud&amp;rsquo;s ideas seeped into public consciousness. How they were taken and deployed by ad-men and marketing gurus to sell our own initimated desires back to ourselves. There is a conceit of individuality and uniqueness - that our mind is our own and the choices we make are ours alone to know and learn from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing, Simultaneity and IV Regression</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/pricing_a_potted_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/pricing_a_potted_history/</guid>
      <description>Demand curve analysis is the academic study of tolerable robbery and stock market manias spike demand curves. You&amp;rsquo;ve likely seen the cobweb like diagrams that chart the trajectories of supply and demand as a function of price. These are aids to estimate the depth of your pockets. Acceptable elascticities of pricing always emerge as a consequence of tolerable changes in demand. A pricing strategy is a question of latitude, how far can we stretch your budget to account for &amp;ldquo;surplus value&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haavelmo&#39;s Autonomous laws in Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/forecasting_grue_timeseries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/forecasting_grue_timeseries/</guid>
      <description>In 1944 Trygve Haavelmo could argue sincerely that the hostility to mathematical statistics in economics was a mistake. He could argue that, in fact, economic questions could be phrased in the language of probability. Today that observation is palpably anachronistic, owing to the current trend of equating economists with soothsayers while expecting similar arcana and spell craft. The reality falls short of magic and is more interesting than the fantasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factor Analysis and Construct Validity in Psychology</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/theoretical_risks_meehl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/theoretical_risks_meehl/</guid>
      <description>In a prescient paper in the 1970s Paul Meehl wrote about the lack of cumulative success in the psychologocial sciences, and how this should be attributed to poor methodology rather than the sheer difficulty of the subject. He elaborates an impressive list of problems for modeling any psychological process. Common themes criss-cross the list and interact with one another in ways which could make you despair for the discipline. So it is, I think, somewhat surprising that Meehl locates the main problem not in the subject, but in the method of significance testing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>