<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Probability on Examined Algorithms</title>
    <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/tags/probability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Probability on Examined Algorithms</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2020 Nathaniel Forde</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 10:19:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nathanielf.github.io/tags/probability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Estimation and Histogram Approximation</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/bayesian_ab_tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/bayesian_ab_tests/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re pretty confident of your recent bet. All the other gamblers at the table have taken the other side of the bet. Just for fun, assume all other gamblers in the casino have bet against you. The game is in the first quarter and things are looking good, but how do you evaluate now whether you should hedge your bets before final quarter is called? This kind of scenario is typical in an imbalanced A/B test where we haven&amp;rsquo;t randomised the samples, and we&amp;rsquo;re letting it ride based entirely on vibes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pooling Information in PYMC</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/pooling_experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/pooling_experiments/</guid>
      <description>Two heads are better than one and fools rarely differ. It&amp;rsquo;s an old trope. A tension to be navigated everytime we combine information across different sources. Can we trust the aggregate opinion? If we poll the masses do the summary statistics measure a common source of variation or represent an crass abstraction over individual particulars? But if we do trust the sources, how far can we generalise from the historic record?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Processes and Inferred Networks</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/spatial_correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/spatial_correlation/</guid>
      <description>Of the varied ways in which you add to the world, you might imagine a modest influence over your social network. Of all those connections their cumulative impact is likely less than you imagine. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re a new parent hopeful to leave a positive impression on your children, but conscious of friends ignored. Attention is a resource, so the periphery of our network may suffer neglect or fall out altogether - some individuals are sacrificed, others deliberately culled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Decisions &amp; Model Comparison </title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/bayes_decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/bayes_decision/</guid>
      <description>Most days we face an infinite horizon of future decisions without being overwhelmed. A sequence of such decisions can compound, or reduce that certainty. But we tend to focus on the exaggerated drama of the momentous choice. Even when change is gradual and cumulative, history tells of a tale of pivot points, epic junctures and transformative events. Two paths diverge in a woods and we choose one. An array of possibilities suddenly open before us, or gets collapsed into a cul de sac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wheat from Chaff: Maximum Entropy and Information</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/wheat_from_chaff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/wheat_from_chaff/</guid>
      <description>There is a rumour of ignorant fish; so involved in the ocean they fail to notice the water around them, what it is and what it could be. There is another cliche about the internet and its denizens drowning in information. There is something to both these images, but the second is too charitable. It suggests a light consistency to the viscous texture of the flow, instead of the congealed sludge that drips down our throat choking off the air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haavelmo&#39;s Autonomous laws in Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/forecasting_grue_timeseries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/forecasting_grue_timeseries/</guid>
      <description>In 1944 Trygve Haavelmo could argue sincerely that the hostility to mathematical statistics in economics was a mistake. He could argue that, in fact, economic questions could be phrased in the language of probability. Today that observation is palpably anachronistic, owing to the current trend of equating economists with soothsayers while expecting similar arcana and spell craft. The reality falls short of magic and is more interesting than the fantasy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>