<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Probability on Examined Algorithms</title>
    <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/tags/probability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Probability on Examined Algorithms</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2020 Nathaniel Forde</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:19:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nathanielf.github.io/tags/probability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Decisions &amp; Model Comparison </title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/bayes_decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/bayes_decision/</guid>
      <description>Most days we face an infinite horizon of future decisions without being overwhelmed. A sequence of such decisions can compound, or reduce that certainty. But we tend to focus on the exaggerated drama of the momentous choice. Even when change is gradual and cumulative, history tells of a tale of pivot points, epic junctures and transformative events. Two paths diverge in a woods and we choose one. An array of possibilities suddenly open before us, or gets collapsed into a cul de sac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wheat from Chaff: Maximum Entropy and Information</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/wheat_from_chaff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/publication/wheat_from_chaff/</guid>
      <description>There is a rumour of ignorant fish; so involved in the ocean they fail to notice the water around them, what it is and what it could be. There is another cliche about the internet and its denizens drowning in information. There is something to both these images, but the second is too charitable. It suggests a light consistency to the viscous texture of the flow, instead of the congealed sludge that drips down our throat choking off the air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haavelmo&#39;s Autonomous laws in Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/forecasting_grue_timeseries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanielf.github.io/post/forecasting_grue_timeseries/</guid>
      <description>In 1944 Trygve Haavelmo could argue sincerely that the hostility to mathematical statistics in economics was a mistake. He could argue that, in fact, economic questions could be phrased in the language of probability. Today that observation is palpably anachronistic, owing to the current trend of equating economists with soothsayers while expecting similar arcana and spell craft. The reality falls short of magic and is more interesting than the fantasy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>